Finding Aid for the Henry Miller Papers LSC.0110
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Correspondence, 1899-1980; 95 boxes (47.5 linear ft.)
  - Main correspondence, ca. 1899-1980; 68 boxes (34 linear ft.)
    - Williams, Jonathan, 1946-1967; 27 items. (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Williams, Lawrence, 1966; 1 items. (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Williams, Mary, undated; 3 items. (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Williams, Owen--Winslow, Edna, 1940-1969; 36 items. (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Winslow, Walker (1 of 5), 1949; 16 items. (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - Winslow, Walker (2 of 5), 1950-1951; 46 items. (Box 66, Folder 10)
    - Winslow, Walker (3 of 5), 1952-1955; 33 items. (Box 66, Folder 11)
    - Winslow, Walker (4 of 5), 1956-1959; 33 items. (Box 66, Folder 12)
    - Winslow, Walker (5 of 5), 1960-1967; 43 items. (Box 66, Folder 13)
    - Winsor & Newton--Wise, Peter Merrill, 1953-1964; 11 items. (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Witherspoon, Bill (1 of 3), 1963-1964; 31 items. (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Witherspoon, Bill (2 of 3), 1965-1967; 41 items. (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Witherspoon, Bill (3 of 3), 1968-1969; 15 items. (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Witherup--Wong, 1945-1965; 55 items. (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Wood, Jasper, 1943-1946; 17 items. (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Wood, Myron, 1945-1965; 19 items. (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - Wood, Paula--Woodcock, 1953-1968; 10 items. (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Woodford, Jack, 1949-1961; 21 items. (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - Woodman--Wright, Cedric, 1944-1968; 50 items. (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - Wright, Eugene, 1956-1965; 15 items. (Box 67, Folder 11)
    - Wright, George, 1951-1952; 8 items. (Box 67, Folder 12)
    - Wright, Howard and Nancy--Wright, Joan, 1952-1958; 4 items. (Box 67, Folder 13)
    - Wright, John C., 1943-1957; 27 items. (Box 67, Folder 14)
    - Wright, Robert--Wyss, 1945-1968; 36 items. (Box 67, Folder 15)
    - Yale Literary Review--Young, Lafayette, 1944-1968; 52 items. (Box 146, Folder 1)
    - Young Men and Young Women's Hebrew Assoc.--Yunkers, 1950-1961; 19 items. (Box 146, Folder 2)
    - Young, Noel and Margaret, 1951-1957; 21 items. (Box 146, Folder 3)
    - Young, Robert, 1949-1968; 38 items. (Box 146, Folder 4)
    - Zadkine, Ossip, 1950-1951; 7 items. (Box 146, Folder 5)
    - Zaentz--Ziff-Davis Publishing Company, 1944-1966; 52 items. (Box 146, Folder 6)
    - Zilzer, Gyula, 1943-1968; 32 items. (Box 146, Folder 7)
    - Zimet--Zygala, 1949-1963; 16 items. (Box 146, Folder 8)
  - Deposited correspondence, 1968-1969; 2 boxes (1 linear ft.)
    This subseries consists of assorted correspondence, deposited in the library between 1968-1970. Letters from major correspondents are arranged alphabetically in folders labeled A-Z. Unidentified correspondents are filed under "Unidentified" in the U sequence of the alphabet. Miscellaneous correspondence and fan mail is unsorted and filed at the end of the A-Z folders.
    - A, 1968-1969 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - B, 1968-1969 (Box 68, Folder 2)
      Includes letters from Brassaï.
    - C, 1968-1969 (Box 68, Folder 3)
      Includes letters from Miriam Cendrars.
    - D, 1968-1969 (Box 68, Folder 4)
      Includes letters from Lawrence Durrell.
    - E, 1968-1969 (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - F, 1968-1969 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - G, 1968-1969 (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - H, 1968-1969 (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - K, 1968-1969 (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - L, 1968-1969 (Box 68, Folder 10)
      Letters from Jon and Louise Webb, Loujon Press.
    - M, 1968-1969 (Box 68, Folder 11)
      Includes letters from Tony Miller.
    - N, 1968-1969 (Box 68, Folder 12)
    - O, 1968-1969 (Box 68, Folder 13)
    - P, 1968-1969 (Box 68, Folder 14)
      Includes letters from Alfred Perlès.
    - R, 1968-1969 (Box 68, Folder 15)
      Includes letters from Abraham Rattner.
    - S, 1968-1969 (Box 68, Folder 16)
    - T, 1968-1969 (Box 68, Folder 17)
    - U, 1968-1969 (Box 68, Folder 18)
    - Unidentified correspondents, 1968-1969 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - V, 1968-1969 (Box 69, Folder 2)
      Letters from Jean Verame.
    - W, 1968-1969 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - X-Z, 1968-1969 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (1 of 6), 1968 (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (2 of 6), 1969 (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (3 of 6), 1969 (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (4 of 6), 1969 (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (5 of 6), 1969 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (6 of 6), 1969 (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Deposited correspondence, 1970; 3 boxes (1.5 linear ft.)
    This subseries consists of assorted correspondence, deposited in the library circa 1970. Letters from major correspondents are arranged alphabetically in folders labeled A-Z. Miscellaneous correspondence and fan mail is unsorted and filed at the end of the A-Z folders.
    - A, 1970 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - B, 1970 (Box 70, Folder 4)
      Includes letter from Brassaï.
    - C, 1970 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - D, 1970 (Box 70, Folder 6)
      Includes letter from Beauford Delaney.
    - E, 1970 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - F, 1970 (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - G, 1970 (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - H, 1970 (Box 70, Folder 10)
    - J, 1970 (Box 70, Folder 11)
    - K, 1970 (Box 70, Folder 12)
    - L, 1970 (Box 70, Folder 13)
    - M, 1970 (Box 70, Folder 14)
    - N, 1970 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - O, 1970 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - P, 1970 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - R, 1970 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - S, 1970 (Box 71, Folder 5)
      Letters from Arthur Secunda and Carlos Suarès.
    - T, 1970 (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - U, 1970 (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - V, 1970 (Box 71, Folder 8)
      Letters from Jean Verame and Jean Varda.
    - W, 1970 (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - X-Z, 1970 (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (1 of 8), 1970 (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (2 of 8), 1970 (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (3 of 8), 1970 (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (4 of 8), 1970 (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (5 of 8), 1970 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (6 of 8), 1970 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (7 of 8), 1970 (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (8 of 8), 1970 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Deposited correspondence, 1971; 3 boxes (1.5 linear ft.)
    This subseries consists of assorted correspondence, deposited in the library circa 1971. Letters from major correspondents are arranged alphabetically in folders labeled A-Z. Unidentified correspondents are filed under "Unidentified" in the U sequence of the alphabet. Miscellaneous correspondence and fan mail is unsorted and filed at the end of the A-Z folders.
    - A, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - B, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 3)
      Letters from Brassaï.
    - C, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - D, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - E, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - F, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 7)
      Letters from Miriam Cendrars.
    - G, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - H, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - J, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - K, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 11)
    - L, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 12)
    - M, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 13)
      Letter from Norman Mailer.
    - N, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 14)
    - O, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 15)
    - P, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 16)
      Letters from Alfred Perlès.
    - Q, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 17)
    - R, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 18)
      Letters from Lucy Schmidt Reichel.
    - S, 1971 (Box 73, Folder 19)
      Letter from Carlo Suarès.
    - T, 1971 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - U, 1971 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Unidentified correspondents, 1971 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - V, 1971 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - W, 1971 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (1 of 11), 1971 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (2 of 11), 1971 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (3 of 11), 1971 (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (4 of 11), 1971 (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (5 of 11), 1971 (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (6 of 11), 1971 (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (7 of 11), 1971 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (8 of 11), 1971 (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (9 of 11), 1971 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (10 of 11), 1971 (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (11 of 11), 1971 (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Deposited correspondence, 1972; 3 boxes (1.5 linear ft.)
    This subseries consists of assorted correspondence, deposited in the library circa 1972. Letters from major correspondents are arranged alphabetically in folders labeled A-Z. Unidentified correspondents are filed under "Unidentified" in the U sequence of the alphabet. Miscellaneous correspondence and fan mail is unsorted and filed at the end of the A-Z folders.
    - A, 1972 (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - B, 1972 (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - C, 1972 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - D, 1972 (Box 76, Folder 7)
      Letter from Beauford Delaney.
    - E, 1972 (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - F, 1972 (Box 76, Folder 9)
      Letters from Wallace Fowlie and Federico Fellini.
    - G, 1972 (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - H, 1972 (Box 76, Folder 11)
    - J, 1972 (Box 76, Folder 12)
    - K, 1972 (Box 76, Folder 13)
    - L, 1972 (Box 76, Folder 14)
    - M, 1972 (Box 76, Folder 15)
    - N, 1972 (Box 76, Folder 16)
      Includes letters from Anaïs Nin.
    - O, 1972 (Box 76, Folder 17)
    - P, 1972 (Box 76, Folder 18)
      Includes letters from Alfred Perlès
    - R, 1972 (Box 76, Folder 19)
      Letters from Abraham Rattner and Jean Renoir.
    - S, 1972 (Box 76, Folder 20)
    - T, 1972 (Box 76, Folder 21)
    - U, 1972 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Unidentified correspondents, 1972 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - V, 1972 (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - W, 1972 (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (1 of 7), 1972 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (2 of 7), 1972 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (3 of 7), 1972 (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (4 of 7), 1972 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (5 of 7), 1972 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (6 of 7), 1972 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (7 of 7), 1972 (Box 78, Folder 4)
  - Deposited correspondence, 1973; 2 boxes (1 linear ft.)
    This subseries consists of assorted correspondence, deposited in the library circa 1973. Letters from major correspondents are arranged alphabetically in folders labeled A-Z. Miscellaneous correspondence and fan mail is unsorted and filed at the end of the A-Z folders. Unidentified correspondents are filed under "Unidentified" in the U sequence of the alphabet.
    - A, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - B, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 2)
      Letter from Brassaï.
    - C, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - D, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - E, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - G, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - H, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - J, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - K, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 9)
    - L, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 10)
    - M, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 11)
    - N, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 12)
    - O, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 13)
    - P, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 14)
    - R, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 15)
      Letters from Man Ray and Abraham Rattner.
    - S, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 16)
    - T, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 17)
    - U, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 18)
    - Unidentified correspondents, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 19)
    - V, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 20)
    - W, 1973 (Box 79, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (1 of 5), 1973 (Box 79, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (2 of 5), 1973 (Box 79, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (3 of 5), 1973 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (4 of 5), 1973 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (5 of 5), 1973 (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Deposited correspondence, 1974; 2 boxes (1 linear ft.)
    This subseries consists of assorted correspondence, deposited in the library circa 1974. Letters from major correspondents are arranged alphabetically in folders labeled A-Z. Unidentified correspondents are filed under "Unidentified" in the U sequence of the alphabet. Miscellaneous correspondence and fan mail is unsorted and filed at the end of the A-Z folders.
    - A, 1974 (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - B, 1974 (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - C, 1974 (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - D, 1974 (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - F, 1974 (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - G, 1974 (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - H, 1974 (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - J, 1974 (Box 83, Folder 8)
    - K, 1974 (Box 83, Folder 9)
    - L, 1974 (Box 83, Folder 10)
    - M, 1974 (Box 83, Folder 11)
    - N, 1974 (Box 83, Folder 12)
    - O, 1974 (Box 83, Folder 13)
    - P, 1974 (Box 83, Folder 14)
    - R, 1974 (Box 83, Folder 15)
    - S, 1974 (Box 83, Folder 16)
    - T, 1974 (Box 83, Folder 17)
    - U, 1974 (Box 83, Folder 18)
    - Unidentified correspondents, 1974 (Box 83, Folder 19)
    - V, 1974 (Box 83, Folder 20)
    - W, 1974 (Box 83, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (1 of 5), 1974 (Box 83, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (2 of 5), 1974 (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (3 of 5), 1974 (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (4 of 5), 1974 (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (5 of 5), 1974 (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - Deposited correspondence, 1975; 3 boxes (1.5 linear ft.)
    This subseries consists of assorted correspondence, deposited in the library circa 1975. Letters from major correspondents are arranged alphabetically in folders labeled A-Z. Miscellaneous correspondence and fan mail is unsorted and filed at the end of the A-Z folders.
    - A, 1975 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - B, 1975 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - C, 1975 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - D, 1975 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - F, 1975 (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - G, 1975 (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - H, 1975 (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - I, 1975 (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - J, 1975 (Box 87, Folder 10)
    - K, 1975 (Box 87, Folder 11)
    - L, 1975 (Box 87, Folder 12)
    - M, 1975 (Box 87, Folder 13)
    - N, 1975 (Box 87, Folder 14)
    - O, 1975 (Box 87, Folder 15)
    - P, 1975 (Box 87, Folder 16)
    - R, 1975 (Box 87, Folder 17)
      Letter from Jean Renoir.
    - S, 1975 (Box 87, Folder 18)
    - T, 1975 (Box 87, Folder 19)
    - U, 1975 (Box 87, Folder 20)
    - W, 1975 (Box 87, Folder 21)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (1 of 9), 1975 (Box 87, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (2 of 9), 1975 (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (3 of 9), 1975 (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (4 of 9), 1975 (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (5 of 9), 1975 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (6 of 9), 1975 (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (7 of 9), 1975 (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (8 of 9), 1975 (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (9 of 9), 1975 (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - Deposited correspondence, 1976; 2 boxes (1 linear ft.)
    This subseries consists of assorted correspondence, deposited in the library circa 1976. Letters from major correspondents are arranged alphabetically in folders labeled A-Z. Unidentified correspondents are filed under "Unidentified" in the U sequence of the alphabet. Miscellaneous correspondence and fan mail is unsorted and filed at the end of the A-Z folders.
    - A, 1976 (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - B, 1976 (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - C, 1976 (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - D, 1976 (Box 91, Folder 4)
    - E, 1976 (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - F, 1976 (Box 91, Folder 6)
    - G, 1976 (Box 91, Folder 7)
    - H, 1976 (Box 91, Folder 8)
    - I, 1976 (Box 91, Folder 9)
    - J, 1976 (Box 91, Folder 10)
      Letter from Erica Jong.
    - K, 1976 (Box 91, Folder 11)
    - L, 1976 (Box 91, Folder 12)
    - M, 1976 (Box 91, Folder 13)
    - N, 1976 (Box 91, Folder 14)
    - O, 1976 (Box 91, Folder 15)
    - P, 1976 (Box 91, Folder 16)
    - R, 1976 (Box 91, Folder 17)
    - S, 1976 (Box 91, Folder 18)
      Letter from Barbara Sanford.
    - T, 1976 (Box 91, Folder 19)
    - U, 1976 (Box 91, Folder 20)
    - Unidentified correspondents, 1976 (Box 91, Folder 21)
    - W, 1976 (Box 91, Folder 22)
    - X-Z, 1976 (Box 91, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (1 of 8), 1976 (Box 91, Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (2 of 8), 1976 (Box 95, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (3 of 8), 1976 (Box 95, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (4 of 8), 1976 (Box 95, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (5 of 8), 1976 (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (6 of 8), 1976 (Box 147, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (7 of 8), 1976 (Box 147, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters (8 of 8), 1976 (Box 147, Folder 3)
  - Deposited correspondence, 1977-1979; 7 boxes (3.5 linear ft.)
    This subseries consists of assorted correspondence, deposited in the library between 1977-1979. Letters from major correspondents are arranged alphabetically in folders labeled A-Z. Unidentified correspondents are filed under "Unidentified" in the U sequence of the alphabet. Miscellaneous correspondence and fan mail is unsorted and filed at the end of the A-Z folders.
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters, 1978-1979 (Box Unknown container 198 for instance of Miscellaneous unsorted letters)
    - A, 1977-1979 (Box 147, Folder 4)
    - B, 1977-1979 (Box 147, Folder 5)
    - C, 1977-1979 (Box 147, Folder 6)
    - D, 1977-1979 (Box 147, Folder 7)
    - E, 1977-1979 (Box 147, Folder 8)
    - F, 1977-1979 (Box 147, Folder 9)
    - G, 1977-1979 (Box 147, Folder 10)
    - H, 1977-1979 (Box 147, Folder 11)
    - K, 1977-1979 (Box 147, Folder 12)
    - L, 1977-1979 (Box 147, Folder 13)
    - M, 1977-1979 (Box 147, Folder 14)
    - N, 1977-1979 (Box 148, Folder 1)
    - O, 1977-1979 (Box 148, Folder 2)
    - P, 1977-1979 (Box 148, Folder 3)
    - R, 1977-1979 (Box 148, Folder 4)
    - S, 1977-1979 (Box 148, Folder 5)
    - T, 1977-1979 (Box 148, Folder 6)
    - U, 1977-1979 (Box 148, Folder 7)
    - Unidentified correspondents, 1977-1979 (Box 148, Folder 8)
    - W, 1977-1979 (Box 148, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters, 1977 (Box 148, Folder 11)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters, 1977 (Box 148, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters, 1977 (Box 149, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters, 1977 (Box 149, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters, 1977 (Box 149, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous unsorted letters, 1977 (Box 149, Folder 4)
- Manuscripts, 1896-1980; 33 boxes, 4.5 oversized boxes (18.5 linear ft.)
  This series consists of manuscripts for articles, essays, monographs, prefaces, and reviews by Henry Miller. It also contains manuscripts by other people, including some prominent writers, who sent their manuscripts to Miller for his comments and review.
  Arranged in subseries A-C as follows:
  A. Literary manuscripts by Miller, 1896-1978 (26 boxes)
  B. Prefaces and reviews by Miller, 1939-1964 (1 box)
  C. Manuscripts by others, 1932-1980 (10 boxes).
  - Literary manuscripts by Miller, 1896-1978; 22 boxes, 4.5 oversized boxes (13 linear ft.)
    This subseries consists of original typescript and holograph manuscripts by Miller, and galleys, proofs, and layouts for Miller's books. Items are arranged alphabetically by the title of the published work. Book chapters and essays published in compilations are listed under the title of the larger work. Unpublished works are listed alphabetically by the supplied title.
    - "L'age d'or", undated; 2 items. (Box 81, Folder 1)
      Two drafts, typescripts. Essay about Louis Buñuel's film "L'age d'or" written soon after the film was screened in Paris in 1930.
    - The Air Conditioned Nightmare. "Arkansas and the great pyramid", undated; 2 items. (Box 81, Folder 2)
      Typescript with holograph corrections, and one carbon copy. Dedicated to Albert Pike and "Coin" Harvey.
    - The Air-Conditioned Nightmare. "A day in the park", undated; 1 items. (Box 81, Folder 3)
      Typescript with holograph corrections.
    - The Air Conditioned Nightmare. "The desert rat", undated; 1 items. (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - The Air-Conditioned Nightmare. "From Grand Canyon to Burbank", undated; 1 items. (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - The Air-Conditioned Nightmare. "Good news! God is love!", undated; 2 items. (Box 81, Folder 6)
      Typescript with holograph corrections, boxed in a red linen case. Includes one carbon copy.
    - The Air-Conditioned Nightmare. "Letter to Lafayette", undated; 1 items. (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - The Air-Conditioned Nightmare. "Erotica", undated; 1 items. (Box 81, Folder 8)
      Incomplete carbon typescript pertaining to "Erotica." Inscribed in pencil, "Erotica films, etc."
    - The Air-Conditioned Nightmare. "The Negro", undated; 2 items. (Box 81, Folder 9)
      Typescript with holograph corrections, and one carbon copy. Inscribed in pencil, "Unfinished pages of section never used."
    - The Air-Conditioned Nightmare. Miscellaneous manuscripts, undated; 1 items. (Box 81, Folder 10)
      Carbon typescript with holograph corrections, stacked in a typewriter paper box. Includes fragments and notes pertaining to various sections.
    - The Air-Conditioned Nightmare. "A night with Jupiter", undated; 1 items. (Box 82, Folder 1)
      Typescript.
    - The Air-Conditioned Nightmare. "Plans", undated; 4 items. (Box 82, Folder 2)
      Holograph notes in ink.
    - The Air-Conditioned Nightmare. "Potpourri", undated; 3 items. (Box 82, Folder 3)
      Typescript with holograph corrections. Includes manuscripts entitled "To be a cow in a park!" and "Miscellaneous fragments," some unpublished.
    - The Air-Conditioned Nightmare. "Preface", 1941; 2 items. (Box 82, Folder 4)
      Typescript with holograph corrections, 27 leaves, boxed in a red linen case. Includes the original corrected preface, a carbon typescript with holograph corrections.
    - The Air-Conditioned Nightmare. "Soirée in Hollywood", undated; 1 items. (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - The Air-Conditioned Nightmare. "The soul of anaesthesia", undated; 4 items. (Box 82, Folder 6)
      Assorted typescripts. Includes the titles: "Does God inhabit the penitentiary?," "One of our ex-convicts," and "Excerpt from chapter on prison." Published by New Directions, New York, 1945.
    - The Air-Conditioned Nightmare. "Vive la France!", undated; 1 items. (Box 82, Folder 7)
    - The Air-Conditioned Nightmare. "With Edgar Varese in the Gobi Desert", undated; 1 items. (Box 82, Folder 8)
    - "The all-intelligent explosive rocket", undated; 1 items. (Box 82, Folder 9)
      Unpublished typescript.
    - Aller Retour New York. "Preface" and "Postface", 1954-1958; 6 items. (Box 82, Folder 10)
      Typescripts, assorted drafts. Titles include "Preface," "Postface," and "Reunion in Barcelona" which was published separately by Scorpion Press in 1959. Also includes one letter from Walter Freeman regarding the work.
    - Als Wir Noch Lausbuben Waren. "An anecdotal remembrance for the Franz Schneider Verlag", 1965-1966; 4 items. (Box 82, Folder 11)
      "Final draft," typescript with holograph corrections, 15 leaves. Also includes a German translation of the manuscript and page proofs of the article. Also includes 1 letter from Franz Schneider to Miller regarding Miller's contribution to the book.
    - "Another word of two on Rimbaud", 1962; 1 items. (Box 82, Folder 12)
      Typescript, 3 leaves. Includes postcard to Miller by an unidentified person regarding Rimbaud.
    - "Answers to questionnaire for Playboy", undated; 1 items. (Box 82, Folder 13)